<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on ZySec</title>
    <link>https://zysec-space.github.io/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on ZySec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>mohammadzanil@gmail.com (Mohammed Zanil)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mohammadzanil@gmail.com (Mohammed Zanil)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 12:03:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://zysec-space.github.io/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>cURL – Working with forms</title>
        <link>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/curl_forms/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 12:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>mohammadzanil@gmail.com (Mohammed Zanil)</author>
        <guid>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/curl_forms/</guid>
        <description>In the first cURL post, I wrote about how to download files using cURL. I recently got an opportunity to work with forms using cURL. In this post, I will describe about how I used cURL to send a POST request to page containing a form. The objective was to obtain the response from the server after submitting a form.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Commando VM – a PenTest distro for the windows users</title>
        <link>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/commandovm/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>mohammadzanil@gmail.com (Mohammed Zanil)</author>
        <guid>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/commandovm/</guid>
        <description>For long, penetration testers and security enthusiasts have been using tools that are natively built around the linux platform. There are few linux flavours dedicated entirely for this purpose. BackTrack, Kali and Parrot OS are few among them.
FireEye, a Cyber Security Solutions Provider, has released a new product which runs on top of the windows OS to install more than 140 tools including the most popular ones such as Nmap, Wireshark, Burp Suite, Mimikatz, Hashcat etc.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>NSA reveals Ghidra</title>
        <link>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/ghidra/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 12:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>mohammadzanil@gmail.com (Mohammed Zanil)</author>
        <guid>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/ghidra/</guid>
        <description>Ghidra is a Software Reverse Engineering (SRE) framework developed by the National Security Agency which was announced during the RSA 2019 conference. NSA has made the tool available as an open source software allowing and accepting contributions from the community. Its functionality is similar to other reverse engineering softwares such as IDA, Binary Ninja, Capstone etc.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Crunch – Create your own wordlist</title>
        <link>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/crunch/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 12:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>mohammadzanil@gmail.com (Mohammed Zanil)</author>
        <guid>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/crunch/</guid>
        <description>Crunch is a wordlist generator useful for password cracking. Sometimes, you don’t want to use large precomputed wordlists and instead you may want to create your own. Crunch is your solution! It is a small but powerful command line tool allowing you to specify the criteria for the wordlists and generate it for you.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sublist3r – Subdomain enumeration</title>
        <link>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/sublister/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 12:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>mohammadzanil@gmail.com (Mohammed Zanil)</author>
        <guid>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/sublister/</guid>
        <description>Sublist3r is an information gathering tool written in python for subdomain enumeration. This tool uses OSINT or Open Source Intelligence to gather information from various search engines such as Google, Yahoo, Baidu, Bing and so on.
The tools is available on GitHub which can be setup by cloning the git repository as below:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>cURL – Command line URL tool</title>
        <link>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/curl/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 12:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>mohammadzanil@gmail.com (Mohammed Zanil)</author>
        <guid>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/curl/</guid>
        <description>cURL doesn’t stand for command line URL tool but it is one of the tools available for transferring of files seamlessly through the terminal. cURL is considered an abbreviation for Client URL Request Library. cURL supports multiple network protocols allowing to access files through HTTP(S), FTP(S), SCP to name a few.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CrypTool – Fun way to learn Cryptography</title>
        <link>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/cryptool/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 12:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>mohammadzanil@gmail.com (Mohammed Zanil)</author>
        <guid>https://zysec-space.github.io/posts/cryptool/</guid>
        <description>A great application for newcomers as well as for the experienced to learn more about various cryptographic protocols and algorithms. CrypTool provides an intuitive graphical interface to play around with various settings of any cryptographic algorithm. Using the tool, one can understand the importance of key length and choice of characters for any encryption scheme.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>